# Saurabh Patil

Mobile: +91-7218814738 Location: Pune, Maharashtra

#### **EDUCATION**

## College of Engineering, Pune

Pune, India

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Engineering

Aug 2018 - June 2021

Email: saurabhpatil2199@gmail.com

Courses: Operating Systems, Data Structures, Analysis Of Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Networking, Databases

# SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: Python, C, Java, Golang

Frameworks: Openapi, Django

• Tools: Kubernetes, GIT, MySQL, SQLite, Gradle

• Platforms: Linux, Windows, VScode, XFS

• Other experience: JSON, YAML, REST API, Fio benchmarking tool, shell scripting

#### Professional Summary

An experienced professional having expertise working with microservice architecture, worked on product which is highly scalable and fault tolerant. Experience working under data and storage domain applying technical design and development skills having ability to own my tasks and gaining proficiency working on technologies like kubernetes, Golang, C, Python. Effective at working on feature development, bug fixes and adapting to the agile methodology. Open to work on new technologies and products. Prefer to work as an Backend Developer.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Veritas Technologies llc

Pune, Maharashtra

June 2021 - Present

- $Software\ Engineer\ (Full-time)$ 
  - $\circ \ \ Working \ under \ ASDS (Application \ and \ Software \ defined \ storage) \ product \ architecture \ and \ innovations \ team.$
  - Contributing to the design and development of the new product IS-X (InfoScale next generation) which aims being cloud native and providing data storage, data backup, data recovery and high availability services to the customers.
  - I'm part of the Control plane design team handling the responsibilities to orchestrate operations to the Data plane. As part of it developing a REST API for handling the operations which could be user initiated or triggered events from Data plane.
  - Developed a service for client applications to communicate with the kubernetes apiserver. This service exposes functionalities for client applications to perform operations on Veritas custom resources.
  - Handled the security aspects of IS-X cluster by providing TLS/SSL support between client application and server. Designed the SSL certificate bootstrapping process for the cluster
  - Contributed to development of handlers to serve the user initiated requests (eg. VolumeCreate, VolumeDelete, CreateSnapshot, etc.)
  - Worked on performance analysis of XFS and BTRFS file system to check the performance difference of this file systems under real life scenarios.

# Veritas Technologies llc

Pune, Maharashtra

Jan 2021 - June 2021

Software development Engineer (Internship)

- o Build process migration from Ant to Gradle:
- $\circ\,$  Migrated the entire build process of eDP product of veritas from Ant to Gradle
- $\circ~$  Reduced the entire build process time by 20 30 minutes.
- o Provided Parallel execution, performance enhancement Dependency Management to this build process.
- o Audio transcripts generation for audio and video files:
- Worked on opensource libraries like kaldi and vosk to generate audio transcripts of audio and video files.
- o provided 90% 95% accuracy in generated transcripts.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

•	Kubernetes Working with microservices, understanding kubernetes resources and architecture	Issued June 2021 $Udemy$
•	System Programming in C Understanding of Memory management, system calls, processes, threads, file management, etc.	Issued Feb 2022 $Udemy$
•	Golang Golang Programming	Issued Feb 2022 $Udemy$
•	Distributed System Design Understanding of terminologies used for designing largescale systems.	Issued Aug 2022 <i>Udemy</i>

# ACADEMIC/PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Thread Library (C programming, Linux System calls): Developed own thread library in C. As part of it one to one and Many to One threading models were created. Functionalities provided were Creating a thread, Locking and Unlocking thread, Synchronization of threads, Context switching in threads. Referred to POSIX thread library
- Linux Grep Command (C programming, Data Structures): Created a Prototype of Grep command. Provided argument functionalities like (-r , -i, -v, -f , -w, -c, -m , etc.) The Functionalities of this command were referred from the Linux grep command.
- Linux command executing terminal (C Programming, Linux System calls): Provided functionalities for executing linux commands(for eg. gedit helloworld.c will open an editor with file helloworld.c). Other functionalities like pipelining of output and output redirection was implemented.
- Text Summarizer (Python): Implemented a program which was able to summarize the text provided. Used text processing, NLP techniques and Frequency count algorithm for summarization.
- Grievance Redressal portal (Web Development): Created a project for my college for issuing grievances from students regarding any activities. It included functionalities like registration of students and teachers, submission of grievances. Checking status of each grievance.

#### Honors and Awards

- Silver Medalist in Diploma, Information Technology, 2018
- Participation in Hackathon India, Working on project for Government of Assam 2017

# Volunteer Experience

# Web team member at Zest, COEP - 2018 Worked on developing Zest (Sports event of COEP) website. Pune, Maharashtra Aug 2018

Technical committee member at IGNITE, IOPE College
Organized College level Technical events, Worked with team for developing college website
Raigad, Maharashtra
Aug 2016 - Mar 2018